Daniel Morriss

Junior Fullstack Software Developer

Github / Linkedin / Portfolio
Wiltshire, UK / danielmorriss1@gmail.com / +447919 288949

Executive Summary

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python. I have 15 years experience in the Music Industry. I am a valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem solving ability. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

Education

Mar 2023 - Present Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Fullstack Software Development (Accredited by the University West of Scotland)

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019 University of West London London, United Kingdom

Licentiate of the London College of Music - Level 6 Diploma in Music Teaching

Technical Skillset

Technologies		Databases	Frameworks		Version Control
HTML	CSS	MongoDB	Django	jQuery	Git
Javascript	Python	MySQL	Bootstrap		Github

Portfolio Projects

- 1. **Retro Mashup Mayhem** A browser based game inspired by the visuals, sounds and themes of the golden age of arcade games. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Kaboom.js https://github.com/DanMorriss/Retro-Mashup-Mayhem
- 2. **Lumos Online Banking** A mock online banking app linked to an external database. Technologies used: Python, GoogleSheets, Heroku https://github.com/DanMorriss/lumos-online-banking
- 3. Morriss Music A website to promote my online teaching business including resources for students inside a members area. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap. https://github.com/DanMorriss/morriss-music
- 4. **Music Theory Quiz** A browser based quiz to improve your music theory knowledge. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS. JavaScript. https://github.com/DanMorriss/music-theory-quiz
- 5. **Jazz Platform** A website for a monthly Jazz night. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS. https://github.com/DanMorriss/jazz-platform

Collaborative Projects

Hackathon - My team came 1st in the Retro Quest hackathon ran by Code Institute. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Kaboom.js https://github.com/DanMorriss/Retro-Mashup-Mayhem

Work Experience

March 2019 - Present Morriss Music Ltd. Instrument Tuition Newbury/Remote

- Using software and digital services to supply high-quality interactive lessons online, including online booking, automated invoices & reminders.
- Building and maintaining a website to sell music and supply resources for students.
- Production and selling of an online course with interactive app.
- Writing individual learning paths for students to achieve high exam grades in a suitable time frame.

Sept 2016 - March 2019 Touring & Studio Session Musician

- Demonstrating adaptability and problem-solving skills in high-pressure live situations, handling technical and performance-related challenges.
- Working in multiple recording studios utilizing digital and outboard recording equipment to produce tracks and oversee the recording process.
- Exhibited versatility by playing multiple instruments and effectively collaborating with other musicians to achieve the desired sound.

Jan 2006 - Aug 2016 Echotape Band Member

- Contributed to the composition of original music, showcasing creativity and musical collaboration.
- Conducted interviews with various media outlets, representing the band's vision and promoting their work.
- Managing teams during international tours, ensuring smooth logistics and coordinating with booking agents & record companies.

Certificates/Courses

- JS3 by Wes Boz JavaScript (30 hours)
- Conquering Responsive Layouts by Kevin Powell CSS (30 hours)

Additional Information/Interests

- Regular engagement on Slack tech forum, staying updated on industry trends and networking with professionals.
- Maintaining a healthy and active lifestyle, regularly participating in climbing and running.
- Full Drivers License and extensive driving experience.
- Avid reader, particularly enjoy science fiction, fantasy and horror genres.
- Member of the house band in the Newbury Jazz PLatform, a monthly jam night.

References available on request.